[music]
I'm a walker, so I'm going to have a
hard time standing behind here, but I'll
do the best I can. So, I'm Adam Larson,
and a little bit about me. I have three
kids, four cats, somehow that manage a
dog. Uh, I've been a dev for about 21
years. Started professionally in 2004.
I like to joke that I've held literally
every role in a company possible from
unpaid intern to CEO uh and pretty much
everything in between. Most recently as
founder and CTO of Railon, we built very
heavily on top of LLMs and I learned a
ton both about evaluating them, but also
like actually how to actually build on
top of them and provide business value.
It was uh recently acquired. So I'm
currently principal staff engineer at in
Mailchimp. It's acquired three weeks
ago. So, just happened. Um, but I want
to back up a little bit. So, going back
about maybe 18 months, do you guys
remember on X, like every other post was
AI is going to take away all jobs from
engineers. Some new model would come
out, it's the best thing ever. Every
YouTube video that came out was like the
biggest hype thing ever. I kind of got
sick of that personally because like I
would be like man you know you see and
actually I got a great example of this
uh remember long before like long before
came out like YouTube blew up and it was
like this is the best model ever and
within minutes you know reality starts
to set in and they're like you know
they're delaying it and nothing's
happening. So that's really what I
started doing on YouTube is I actually
wanted to come up with a way to share
the stuff that I was learning in the
startup I was working on at the time and
really try to like be realistic like I
did not see a path forward for like a
full replacement for engineers and I
felt a lot of that was just marketing
hype. I did not really see AI advancing
to the level where like we were going to
be able to completely remove the human
in the loop and I felt like a lot of it
was just way too much hype. But it is an
incredible tool like I'm a very like I
love AI coding assistance and that's
sort of the community that I built on u
on GOU coder which is really focused
around like using it effectively but
also knowing its limits and not
overhyping the things that are actually
happening.
So,
Llama 4 came out. I actually started
doing what I'm about to talk about well
before Llama 4, but typical eval would
come, you know, you've got like terminal
uh terminal bench, suede bench, there's
a bunch of other ones out there that
come out. A lot of them back when I was
starting this were the most basic things
that you would learn in like a first
year compsite class. like you would look
at it as like hey write a function to do
this particular thing. Very basic test.
It was not indicative at all of what we
were doing on a day-to-day basis. So
they are improving now. I think
SweetBench is probably one of the better
ones. Terminal Bench is also pretty
decent. For example, here's like a
Sweetbench example where they're
actually taking a commit and they're
actually trying to solve something
that's actually I would still say not at
the complexity that I think we should be
working at, but it is actually heading
in the right direction now for
evaluation. And I think it's important
because we need to be able to at least
somewhat
me like be able to look at benchmarks
and trust them to a certain degree, but
we also need to understand like what
they are measuring and not every one of
them is measuring what we think they
are. Uh, another one that we've got here
is terminal bench. Terminal bench, I
would say, still airs on the side of
like simplicity. Um, and what I like to
think about is like if when we're
actually working, especially in like big
code bases, we're modifying
anywhere from one to 20 files at times.
Like we're working across business
domains. We need it to gather good
codebase context. a lot of the things
that you see like being evowed don't
really do a good job at actually testing
that. So, this is just kind of like an
example of something that I was working
on recently. You know, it's a fairly big
thing. Uh I've worked on it for like a
day. You know, it's 13 commits, 14
different files modified, 2200 lines
added, added some tests and all that
stuff with it. You really are kind of
you're not working in these discrete
patterns. And and that's one of the
flaws that I think we have with like
really evaluating how these LLM actually
work. There's different metrics that we
actually need to look at and try to
understand. I got this like crazy AI
generated roller coaster thing here
because that's what it feels like when
you're working with AI. Like a lot of
times you're just you're you're just
going with it. You're starting new
context windows. You're doing all kinds
of stuff with it. Um it isn't a
straightforward path like a lot of the
benchmarks that we see today. And that's
when I ended up launching um go to eval
which I'll talk through my philosophy
here but the idea behind this this uh I
started this probably a year ago and
I've got to the point where
my objective was we have a new coding
agent coming out every other day and it
was supposedly better in some way. got a
new model coming out every other day and
it's supposedly better in some way, but
we have no real meaningful way that ever
felt to me as a dev that was using it
all the time that it aligned with my
usage, which is everybody stacks a
little bit different, but you know, I'm
full stack. I was doing front-end work.
I was doing backend work. I was doing
infrastructure work in AWS. I was doing
machine learning stuff in Python. So I
have a pretty wide like breath of things
I need to work across, but none of them
seemed like it actually was aligning to
what the benchmarks were saying. So a
lot of my initial tests in V1 were
honestly built around things that I were
working that I was working on. And I had
this philosophy that instead of
modifying one file or having like, you
know, maybe like two or three files, I
was going to have a minimum of eight
files touched, ideally more. So my
version one of this I still very naive
and I'll talk about the kind of the
flaws with it in version one but it
actually did start giving me something
and a lot of the community started
resonating with it too cuz they would
they would align or there might be
slight disagreements but it would align
more with what the sentiment is of
developers than what you know was
happening with the standard benchmarks
out there. But the goal really was let's
make the most complex thing we can and
let's do it in a way that we can now
evaluate the quality of that at the end
which is incredibly difficult to do. So
this is uh just a sample of like some of
the coding agents that I tested this
last month. There's more you know like
even if you you talk to someone here
there's uh the new one that came out
from Gemini uh yesterday that you know
will now need to be tested. Some of them
are more updated than others. Some of
them are better with certain models than
others. So like my original intention
with version one of this was, hey, I
want to use GLM4.6. What is the best
agent that goes with that? And there are
some clear agents that actually do
really well with that model compared to
other ones based on my benchmarks. And I
would say the this is one of the
challenges that actually starts to
happen here is the scale of testing all
these things starts to get pretty
astronomical because as you can see some
of this starts to actually become a
little bit too manual and I'll get into
that in a little bit. Uh these were the
last models that I actually ran through.
So you can see here I would actually
attempt I would actually leave it up to
the community a lot of times. I be like
hey I'm only going to be able to commit
to five this month because it costs a
lot of money. It costs a lot of time.
What are the five you want me to
actually run through? These are the ones
that were voted on. Groc code fast with
one because uh I don't know if you saw
like there's like just crazy usage on
open router with gro code fast and I've
never felt that model was like
incredibly high score but there was like
a lot of usage around it but it it did
fair u the way that I ended up doing
scoring in V1 is
I had static code analysis so what that
means is simple things like I would even
do like linting to make sure it followed
what it did but it's part of the spec
that was actually generated in the
prompt
There were things like you needed to use
a particular library version. So there
were checks that I'd actually manually
build in static code analysis to make
sure it's using the things that I tell
it to use. I would also have a series of
unit tests that if the um if the AI did
exactly what I told it to do, those
would pass with 100%.
And that would be I mean and those are
very timeconuming to actually make as
well. And then if you use uh LLM as a
judge on top of that because we talked
about that in a few few talks today.
Sometimes AI can do things that'll pass
a unit test but it actually isn't doing
a very good you know it's doing things
the wrong way. Uh so it's very important
to actually have like that kind of like
check on it. And I learned a lot about
writing LLM as a judge. In version one
there was a lot of flaws in the way I
did it. version two, what I ended up
learning, AI is really good at yes no
questions. It's really bad at like
giving you a score. So if you say, "Hey,
get rank this on a score of like zero to
10," you're going to get wide variance.
You really need to kind of think about
your LM as a judge as a series of yes no
questions and then that comes together
to be your final score. So sharing some
learning lessons there. The other thing
is you really do need good and bad
examples. You need to be able to say,
"Hey, this is what for this particular
thing, this is what a bad version of
that looks like. This is what a good
version of that looks like. And that
allows it to actually score it um much
more effectively.
And I really did think about this is the
things on the left, they score the same
every time you run it. The thing on the
right, there's going to be variance in
it. And that's just an unfortunate thing
with AI that you have to deal with. The
goal with the LLM as a judge prompt is
to get that variance down as low as
possible. And I got it down within a
5%age. So if I ran the same test
through, you know, five or six times,
the range between the top and bottom
score were with were within 5%. So I
narrowed that in very well. Uh here's an
example of like what version one
actually was where actually was scoring
on a scale of 0 to four. And like I
said, this was actually it was decent,
but I would say very flawed in the in my
initial version of this, which then is
what um kind of led me to want to build
a version two, which I'll talk about.
But it did do some things in my opinion
very well. it. It was really good at
measuring how well an agent and a model
together was at completing a spec
exactly as you kind of detailed it out.
And it was really good at measuring an
AI's ability to do instruction
following.
I learned that some some models are lazy
to where they will do up to a point and
they would just stop and then they and
then I've learned some other models
would do way more work than they
actually you asked them to do. Um, and
it's really interesting because you
start learning these personalities of
models. Like I didn't ask for those five
markdown files, but yet you know Claude
4.5 wanted to give them to me. And so
you start trying to so that's another
flaw with this. Like I I never measured
very well over engineering, which I
still think is something that should be
measured because you shouldn't do more
than I ask you to do. Um, maybe other
people would disagree with me on that.
And this was really the first test other
than like IDER polyglot that really was
trying to test um the agent and the
model performance in a way that allowed
us to kind of be able to make an
objective decision on what tool we
actually wanted to use or if a tool that
came out that said it's better than
everything else was actually better in
any significant way. Um, and to me that
was that was fun. Like I had a ton of
fun like working through that and but it
did some things not so well. And you
will you could talk you could go through
my Discord history. There are people
that would use like an obscure language
like Apex or
uh it's not so obscure but like Elixir
you know it might be doing it might be
scoring well on my test but be
absolutely atrocious at some language or
framework that they're using. And that
makes it incredibly hard because that's
another layer of testing that now needs
to be done because what we've tested now
is we know that in a bounds of certain
technology, certain framework, certain
code, this thing may be really good. But
like let's take it over here. Now we're
using Elixir or PHP or Apex and maybe
it's not so good. So that was a big flaw
with version one.
And then um the AI and harnesses
increased like so much faster than I
could keep up with. I actually had to
retire tests in the first six months.
Like I would I would put out a version
and no none of them would be hit 100%.
And within 6 months a bunch of them were
tapped out. It's like the the the
cycle time and the updates that these
agents had were just astronomical at the
time that I was rolling this out and it
became very timeconuming while building
a company to try to keep up with that.
And the other thing that I think is
incredibly important, more so today than
ever before is codebased navigation and
context gathering. Because now that AI
is as good as it is, I can absolutely
feel a difference from an AI that
actually does it takes its time and
gathers the context it needs to be able
to make a good decision versus an AI
that like reads the first thing and then
jumps to a conclusion. like there is a
massive difference in my mind on the
quality that you get out from whether
it's a plan or whether it's actually an
implementation. So version one did not
do that.
The other thing I learned and this is a
weird diagram. I know it's my beautiful
art. But so back in my days when I was
doing like machine learning, you know,
I'd build a model, I'd run it, I could
get the same I'd build you could run the
same test over and over again. I'm going
to get the same number. With LLMs,
there's so much variance to it. And one
of the tests that I I did, like that one
that I showed you, might have 40 API
calls out to the LLM. little variances
between each of those
can start adding up to pretty
significant differences. So if a
decision is made like on loop two, that
might lead to a very major difference by
the time you're far to the end. So if
you kind of think about this as u the
score across my eval, I might have three
that are relatively close. I might have
one that actually did kind of crappy and
I might have one that's just
exceptionally good. So what I also
struggled with was how do you smooth
that out in a way so that you actually
are kind of normalizing those scores
because it is a it's a non-deterministic
system and there's variables that you
can't take away. There's some variables
you can control but you just can't take
away all of them. Um I can control the
prompt that I go in but I also I can't
provide what Claude is doing in their
server. I can't change what the the LLM
is is doing as it's interpreting the
tokens. So I just think it's very
interesting that um like you will you
will see this more and more and you're
already kind of seeing it as I was kind
of learning this. This was probably
about a year ago when I started kind of
coming like really starting to build the
model of like the challenge of testing
these things. Now what you see is you
see things like codecs and cursor allow
you to be able to do like the same thing
across four or five iterations and then
you can now pick the best one. And it
honestly helps smooth out a lot of this
from an engineering standpoint. Like if
you want to see what uh GPT5.1 is going
to do versus composer one versus
something else, you can now run all of
those in parallel and then pick the best
one. I think it's a really interesting
model. Although it's still a little
wonky in a lot of those systems, but uh
I think it's probably more and more
they're trying to get around this
problem here because if I take claw 4.5
and I run it five times, I'm going to
get five slightly different answers. One
of them is most likely going to be
better than the other.
So version two I so I'm on version two
now. This is what I did. So So
I ended up adding more languages. So C++
got introduced, C# got introduced,
Cotlin, Java, Rust got introduced. I
also um started actually using open
source repos and my own private repos
and snapshotting commits and actually
doing feature additions or bug fixes in
those as part of my evals. And I
introduced one uh Unity 3D because this
was just a request that I got from a lot
of people is that apparently AI um I
used to do gamedev way back in the day,
but apparently AI still struggles a lot
in with gamedev. Like you can do some
things really good, but others it
struggled with so I built a Unity 3D uh
version of that. And then the test went
from being eight files minimum to 12
files minimum. And some of them go up to
20 to 25. So the the complexity
increased a lot. But
think about this in terms of running it.
Um I what because this is my version
one. I could run them all in about six
[snorts] six eight hours, you know,
bouncing around. Version two, I'd have
four computers running
15 different agents is typically what I
try to keep it at. Sometimes people try
to push in more or I'll get messages
about it. And then uh five AI models.
Typically, I would love to do more, but
five. And I I run 20 I have 20 different
evals that I have active. I typically
have three or four that are in like test
mode that I haven't kind of pulled up
yet. And then if I want to run each of
them five times, if I were to do all of
those synchronously, one by one by one
in a single computer, that would be
75,000 minutes. Like I literally
couldn't do it in a month. So I have to
try to run 40 to 50 of those
simultaneously over a period of 24
hours. A lot of that I can automate, but
there's a lot of those tools that I
showed you. You literally can't like for
if you want to use the cursor IDE or
Kira or Klein or or Rue Code, you have
to actually put the put the text in
there, hit the button. Uh sometimes
there's an API error, so you have to
interact with it. It's it's not as um
automatable as I would like that to be.
So, I've gotten to a point now where I
think I've um made it a bit too complex
to be honest because it's hard for me to
actually keep up with the evaluations
that I want to do. But I've been
thinking about a version three and I
think we can do better. And part of the
part of the thing that I had been doing
initially is, you know, you kind of do a
smoke test to make sure that the model
is actually doing the tool calling
right. And it was talked about in a
previous uh talk about there's a bunch
of different ways that tool calling
happens. It's also a very frustrating
thing to test. But there's a way to
decouple that and like we could very
quickly test the ability of a model in
an agent how well they do tool calling
and it and automate the majority of
that. We decouple that and I've got
promptbased versus native. Um I someone
else earlier was calling it virtual tool
calling. I always call it promptbased
tool calling which is like it's just in
the text of the LLM and you have to
parse it out. I don't know if there's
actually an official name. And then the
native tool calling. There's like three
different formats for native tool
calling that also are kind of annoying.
The other thing is I think we can
actually decouple codebased context
gathering. There's probably some really
cool testing that we can actually do to
see how well whether it's using some
sort of um
some sort of system like augment codes
using that's in the cloud that kind of
indexes your codebase and allows it to
search in or using something else. But
there's probably some things that we can
actually do to really measure how well
an agent and a model does at getting the
proper context for the problem before it
starts coding. And I think that could
also be done faster. So rather than me
trying to do it all from beginning to
end, I I'm starting to think about like
how can we break this up into individual
like chunks of tests that ideally
together give us the full picture. And
then the final thing, I tal I alluded to
this before, but ideally there's got to
be a way for us to be able to manage and
understand framework and language
ability uh without having to write a
full end toend test. Like we should be
able to understand GLM4.6 is bad at C++
but amazing at HTML CSS. We should be
able to quickly be able to evaluate
that. I also want to so this is kind of
a this is a tricky thing because
the um
I've actually had several companies
reach out to me and offer to pay me
pretty significant amount of money for
access to my test or for me to work with
them. And I've just never been a fan of
that because in my mind I didn't do any
of this to make money. I did it for fun
to try to help like the community
understand what was good and what was
what was working and what isn't working
and I worry about open sourcing all of
it because I I just have a sneaking
feeling a lot of that start getting
gamed and when that when that happens it
removes the validity of the test and you
can see that immediately with like Llama
4 it nailed all the benchmarks but it
didn't it didn't pass the vibe test it
didn't actually live up to expectations
but I do think there needs to be some um
part of like this framework that I've
been thinking about that needs to be
opened up to everyone and there needs to
be some subset of this that's private
that can stay outside of like the the
game of the gamified LLM game. Um it's
the only way that I think this could
scale because I if you think about this
problem
um
no like this sits outside of all the AI
companies like Claude, you know, they're
going to want Claude code or their
models to be the best. Open AI is going
to want theirs. Cursor is going to want
their agent to be the best. This sits
outside of all of that. So no company is
really going to want to ever fund like
some big initiative like this. But I
think it's important as we're getting
told this new things coming out that we
have some like ability to put checks and
balances on these companies to be like,
"Hey, yeah, you know, Droid is awesome,
but it isn't significantly better than
what's already out there." So, we
shouldn't overhype it. We should just
treat it for like what it is. Uh, and
then I do think we can still keep the
spec and functionality testing. I do
think that's very important, especially
with how good plan modes have gotten
now. uh that we're if we can give if we
can build like these specs that actually
are [snorts] completed you know 80 to
90% of the way there I think that's a
that's an amazing uh boost that we get
as engineers
and one other thing that I spent way too
much time on way too much money on is
so someone alluded this to earlier in a
previous talk but the Chinese models I'm
actually a huge fan of open source I run
a ton open source models. Um I I just my
dream is to be able to like use a lot of
those for everything I want to do. But
what you'll find is if you go to open
router or to whoever is hosting the
models, there's so much variance in the
provider. So I actually built tooling
around detecting the best providers with
certain models based on how they're
quantized, you know, their default
settings and stuff like that. and it put
me in a situation where like this is
another variable that now we're dealing
with. So when I'm when I'm running
something like a quin coder, I'm now
dealing with not only all the variance
of the LM, but I'm also dealing with the
inference and the default settings and
the temperature. So a lot of times I'd
have to actually do initial work where
I'm like at temperature zero it's awful.
At temperature 0.7 it's all right, but
at temperature 0.4 it's great. like I
have to kind of like tone in my own
settings for it and it's just it makes
it really hard uh for any person that
isn't spending that time on there to be
able to hear about a new model go
connect to it and get some good results
out of it. And I think that's going to u
wrap it up here. Maybe just real quick
even anthropic has trouble testing
because I don't know if you guys
remember when claude had that big
degragation and everybody's like man
Claude's definitely worse. I actually
quit using Claude for a while because of
it. This is just such a hard problem
across the board. Uh, but you you can
check out go toe eval.com. I will be
posting some new um stuff with like
Gemini 3 on there soon. I want to see
where that actually lands. But uh yeah,
that's pretty much it.
[applause]
[music]